# **Andrew Yuan**

Senior Full Stack Engineer

Los Angeles, CA, USA •

yuan59880@gmail.com •

+1 804 491 9593 •

linkedin.com/in/andrew-yuan-546084256 •

#### **OBJECTIVE**

A technical team lead with 9 years of experience who values building and working in high-trust teams that have healthy communication, a strong emphasis on ownership, and fast feedback loops. Highly capable of leading technical teams, and cross-team projects. Seeking a position with a tech start-up to be part of an innovative and creative team developing technical platforms and products for a multitude of constituents.

## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE .....

## **Full-Stack Engineer**

Welf Lab, Apr 2020 - Sep 2022

- Developed an e-learning SaaS platform that increased revenue by \$15000 in 2 months with Typescript, Next.js, Node.js, SQL and AWS.
- Built a wedding photo-sharing app from scratch with React, React Native, Ruby on Rails, AWS S3, AWS Lambda.
- Architected a couple of React front ends, created custom React components for UX-library, and conducted extensive UX work using Vue.js by designing and implementing key features and business metrics on a responsive dashboard.
- Maintained and developed features for the Ruby on Rails and Node.js back-end services of the company with Agile methodologies. Deploying to AWS using Lambda/ECS.
- Designed and implemented GraphQL / Rest APIs, backend services using modern OOP practices, and worked on SQL & NoSQL databases.

## **Full-Stack Engineer**

Yaraku, May 2017 - Dec 2019

- Developed and maintained e-commerce applications from scratch, ensured high traffic (500,000 monthly active users) with proper SEO strategy using React.js, Ruby on Rails, NoSQL, and AWS(Elasticsearch, S3, EC2, etc).
- Refactored food delivery system using React, Node.js, PostgreSQL, and AWS, implemented real-time communication using WebSocket, created AWS Lambda functions as trigger, used Material UI as UI library, and integrated with Google APIs.
- Participated in the design and implementation of CI / CD and DevOps processes for agile projects and worked with technologies and platforms such as JavaScript, GIT, Linux, Docker, Ngnix, Jenkins, AWS, and used debugging tools like React-DevTools and Redux-DevTools for faster debugging and reducing debugging time by 50%.
- Integrated Redux and MobX into a number of React-based front-end projects for better state management of React components and created a front-end visualization dashboard using React.js, chart.js and D3.
- Worked on TDD, followed test-first methodology in refactoring projects, wrote unit and integration tests using RSpec, Jest, Mocha, and Cypress, and test coverage was more than 80%.

#### **Full Stack Engineer**

X-Team, May 2015 - Apr 2017

- Refactored event management system and appointment management system for company internal members by migrating from HTML to Angular.
- Maintained a large web application using HTML/CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, PHP(Laravel) framework, and automated monthly supplier payments billing cycle using PHP and MySQL. Ran payment programs on a monthly basis and adjusted conditional business logic through a web interface.
- Turned mockups and designs into actual responsive websites and sliced or extracted the PSDs myself when asked, and finished responsive 3-5 pages in less than 72 hours, given specific time frames ranging from 3 to 5 days.

## **EDUCATION**

#### **Bachelor of Science**

The University of California, Berkeley Sep 2013 - May 2017

> Was an International Collegiate Programming Contest Challenger, and completed tens of local contests.

• Solved hundreds of difficult algorithms and data structure problems.

## ADDITIONAL SKILLS .....

- Ability of communicating with colleagues, clients, product managers and other stakeholders
- Ability of managing multiple projects and handling pressure
- Ability of mentoring other developers with pair-programming and code-review
- Ability of learning new technologies, and frameworks faster than others
- Bilingual in English